# JORDAN ROSS

- jross4797@gmail.com
- h 508-847-4043
- a Roswell, GA 30075

## **SKILLS**

- C, C++, Java, Python, Swift, Javascript
- Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- SQL Server proficiency
- Algorithms and data structures

## **EDUCATION**

University of Michigan - Ann Arbor

Ann Arbor, MI • 06/2020

B.S.E: Computer Science

## APPLICATIONS/TOOLS

Github, Matlab, XCode, Visual Studio, VSCode, React, Ionic, Angular, Django, Firebase, Twilio

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Talented Junior Software Engineer adept at working with customers, team members and project leaders to accomplish software engineering and updating tasks according to timelines. Solid understanding of full development lifecycle. Skilled working with wide range of front- and back-end technologies to produce and evaluate code. Experience with a wide variety of programming languages, software tools, and algorithms.

## **WORK HISTORY**

Avtex Solutions - Software Development Intern Bloomfield Hills, MI • 05/2019 - 08/2019

- Developed, coded and updated solutions for clients using Microsoft CRM software.
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Oversaw testing, troubleshooting and user sampling prior to live deployment.

Nusoft Solutions - Software Development Intern Bloomfield Hills, MI • 05/2018 - 08/2018

- Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for creating new CRM solutions.
- Coordinated with engineering team members to evaluate and improve software interfaces.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Managed milestones from initial steps through final delivery.

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Member of the University of Michigan Men's swimming team 2015 - 2017
- Participated at numerous National Championship competitions
- Competed at the 2016 Olympic Trials in swimming